Everyone and welcome to the whitefly implementation section will provide an overview of the implementation
and some APIs that we'll use from the impressive Viotti development framework.
So first, let's take a look at our implementation overview.
From a high level perspective, meaning what the Abilify application is supposed to do without getting
into too much detail is, first of all, the ESP 32 should start its access point so that other devices
can connect to it.
This enables users to connect to it in order to access information such as sensor data, device information,
connection status and connection information like the IP address, gateway and netmask assigned to the
ESP 32.
Also, we'll have a user option to connect and disconnect from an access point and to display the local
time, etc..
Next, the Wi-Fi application will start an HTTP server and will program this after the wi fi programming
sections, and that web server will support a web page to do everything that I've just mentioned.
Also, the application contains a free autos task that receives cue messages that will use to coordinate
Wi-Fi and web server events, and we'll see more about this later.
By the way, feel free to check out these photos APIs to create, which creates the Q and Q send to
send data to the Q and Q received to receive data which again will use to coordinate the order of events
that occur in our application.
So I won't go into too much details about these because I'm confident that you'll have a general understanding
of how they work.
Once we implement them in the application and later in the course will connect the ESP 32 using previously
saved credentials.
So here's a simplified overview of the Wi-Fi application.
Basically, you'll have a connecting device, either your mobile phone or laptop, etc., which becomes
the station of the ESB 32 soft tape.
When connected, the DHP service from the ESP 32 soft app will dynamically assign an IP to your device
and you'll interact with the ESP 32 via the web page served by the web server.
Also, the P32 itself will start an access point slash station mode and will statically assign an IP
address to the soft API.
The DHP service dynamically assigns an IP address for connecting stations also will specify a maximum
number of stations that are allowed to connect.
And eventually, we'll update the application so that we can connect the SB 32 to an external access
point or router where there's an internet connection.
And this enables us to get the local time using Simple Network Time Protocol or S&P.
And also did keep service from the access point will dynamically assign an IP address to the SPF 30
to an hour application.
Now let's briefly talk about the Wi-Fi driver APIs from the ESB IDF.
So I suggest you visit the impressive documentation here about the Wi-Fi driver and take a couple of
minutes to browse through this.
Also, take a look at the programming model, as well as the fi events that occur in the background.
These events will be picked up by our event handler.
Also, check out the API reference here and feel free to browse through it, but I'll talk about selected
API shortly.
And also look into the network interface documentation here as well.
Just try to take note of the idea behind it and the architecture and scroll down to the programmers
manual, where the Wi-Fi event modes and default initialization I mentioned.
I'll discuss some APIs later from here as well.
All right, so we'll start configuring our Wi-Fi application by defining Wi-Fi settings in the header
file like the side of the USB to the password, the IP address, gateway and netmask, et cetera.
We'll also define the Wi-Fi application for the arduous task, and we can use either API here, but
will actually use the PIN to code version here so that we can specify which core that we want to allocate
the work to as we have two cores available on the ESB 32.
We'll also create an event handler so that certain Wi-Fi and IP events are automatically accounted for
by the Wi-Fi driver.
And at the start of your Wi-Fi application, we'll set up the default configuration by initializing
the TCP IP stack using the ESB network interface and IT function.
And will also create the basic Wi-Fi configuration settings by using the ESP Wi-Fi in IT function.
And by the way, this one must be called before any other Wi-Fi API is called.
Additionally, we'll need to use ISP Wi-Fi set storage, which sets the storage configuration type.
In which case will set the storage type to RAM?
Will then create the default configurations for both the default app and default station interfaces.
Please feel free to follow these links and read up on them in more detail and follow the link for the
default app and default station.
As the API mentioned, we need these to register the default Wi-Fi handlers.
The start of the application also includes defining the SPF 30 to soft day peak configuration will define
the AP settings for members of the wi fi config structure, which in this case will want to update selected
soft AP structure members listed here.
And the ESPN network interface said IP info sets the IP address of the soft AP and ESPN network interface,
D.H. CPS starts the DHP service for any connecting stations to the ESPN Thirty two so that IP addresses
can be dynamically assigned by the ESPN.
Also, S.P. Rifai, I said mode sets the mode, whether it's a mode, station mode or a station mode,
which is the mode that we will use and ESP Wi-Fi said Config sets the configuration of the access point
based on the Wi-Fi config structure members that we have previously set.
And S.P. Wi-Fi set bandwidth will use to set the bandwidth at 20 megahertz.
Additionally, we'll use ISP Wi-Fi, said Power Save, and we're going to set it to none because we
will not use power saving in this application.
Finally, we can call ISP wi fi start once we have done all of this, which starts wi fi in the mode
pre-specified, which in our case is wi fi mode app station mode.
All right, so feel free to keep this document open as we go through the programming section, if you
need to refer back to what's going on and I'll see you there.